ILGWU Local 132. Managers' Correspondence 5780/076
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Local 132. Managers' Correspondence
1949-1976
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Menist, Joel
Eisenberg, Sam
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). Local 132
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/076
3.5 cubic feet
3.5 linear ft.
Correspondence.
The collection consists of correspondence of Local 132's managers, meeting minutes, and the local publication.
6322364
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 14, 2008
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Local 132 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), also known as the Plastic, Moulders and Novelty Workers' Union, was chartered in 1917 and based in New York, New York.
Scope and Contents
The records consist primarily of two series of correspondence of Local 132's managers, Joel Menist and Sam Eisenberg, between 1954 and 1975. The correspondence details administrative matters within the local and contains replies to letters from members to the local office, communication with the Health and Welfare Benefits Department discussing contract agreements, and the ILGWU correspondence more or less includes memos and letters that went out from the International to the locals and departments.
Another component of the collection is correspondence with various firms and manufacturers the local dealt with. These are interesting in that they are not the normal garment shop, but instead plastic and parts manufacturers. There is information on the production of plastic as well as the shortage in the 1970s. The records offer another dimension to the garment industry by illustrating the wide range of work, companies, and productsparticularly plastics, molds and parts.
The final component of the collection includes minutes of Local 132's Executive Board and Health and Welfare Fund Board, as well as a few issues of the local's publication, Local 132 News.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records
Plastics workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Plastics -- Molding -- United States; Eisenberg, Sam; Menist, Joel; A.B.S. Manufacturing Co.; Beth Button Novelty Co.; E.P. Mueller & Engineering; Empire Records; Empire Zipper; Garrary Plastics; Gary Enterprises Inc.; Gibraltar Manufacturing Co.; Harrison Co. Inc.; I. Miller and Bro.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 132; John Rie Inc.; Lerner, Corwin & Young Inc.; Lyndas Jewelry Creation; Miller Brass Fitting; Miller Plastics, Inc.; Monarch Jewelry; Nasco Corp.; National Ribbon Co.; Pender Plastics Co.; Pilot Rubber Plastic Corp.; Plastic Products Manufacturers Association; Plas-Trix Co. Inc.; Rolling Eyes Manufacturing Co.; Silver Park Records Inc.; Thomas Manufacturing Corp.; Whitestone Harrison Corp.; Yorklyn Industries Inc.
6322364
- Correspondence, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  July - September, 1975
- Correspondence, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  April - June, 1975
- Correspondence, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  January - March, 1975
- Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  October - December, 1974
- Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  July - September, 1974
- Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  April - June, 1974
- Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  January - March, 1974
- Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  August - December, 1973
- Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  January - July, 1973
- Health and Welfare Fund, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Association Negotiations (Sheldon Edelman), 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Association Negotiations, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Association Negotiations and Mediation Board, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Association Negotiations, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Deborah Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- G.E. Strike, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Local 132 - 1968 Campaign (Box 1, Folder 18)
- ILGWU 1970 and 1972 Campaign Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Local 132 - 1966 Campaign (Box 1, Folder 20)
- 1968 ILGWU 33rd Convention, 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Resolutions 1968 Convention
- 1971 ILGWU 34th Convention, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- ILGWU Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- ILGWU Correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- ILGWU Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- ILGWU Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- ILGWU Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- ILGWU National Retirement Fund, 1964-1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- ILGWU Strike Reports, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Blank and completed forms
- Labor Day Parade, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Liberal Party, 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Lieberman, Katz and Aronson, 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Lieberman, Aronson and Rosenberg, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Lieberman, Aronson and Rosenberg, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Local 132 Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Local 132 Affairs. Joel Menist Retirement, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Local 132 Census, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Local 810 I.B.T., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Local 810, 1967-1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- 1971 Local Elections, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- 1965 Elections, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- 1968 Local Elections, 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Local 132. Financial Report, 1960-1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Local Unions. ILGWU, 1960-1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Mayor's Committee on Exploitation, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Bernard H. Mazur, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Bernard H. Mazur, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Mazur Dontzin and Mazur, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Mazur Dontzin and Mazur, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Mazur and Dontzin Correspondence, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Plastic Shortage, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Plastic Products Manufacturers Association, 1965-1973 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- United Optical Workers Union, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Workman Circle, 1961-1970 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- United Farms Workers, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- A.B.S. Manufacturing Co., 1961-1969 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Allison Corp., 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Art Pearl Works, 1961-1965 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Aur-O-Loy Plating Co., 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- B and B Hanger Co., 1966 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Ben Nanger Company, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Bennett Heat Treating Co., 1961 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Beth Button Novelty Co., 1961-1965 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Boller Finishing Corp., 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Brody Plastics Corp., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Brooklyn Plastics Co., 1964 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Budgee Products, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Budgee Bra Back Corp., 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Cameo Button Corp., 1965 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Central Plastics, 1962-1967 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Central Button Works Inc., 1961 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Chatham Button Co., 1964-1970 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Corley Manufacturing Co., 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Custom Cellulosic Inc., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Dorsil Company Inc., 1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Empire Records, 1956-1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Empire Zipper, 1961-1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Falcon Plastic Co., 1960 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Farragut Plastic Corp., 1961 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Flama Record Corp., 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Flexigrip Inc., 1962 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Fluorescent, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Garrary Plastics, 1960-1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Gary Enterprises Inc., 1961-1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Gibraltar Manufacturing Co., 1959-1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Hardy Plastics, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Harrison Co. Inc., 1961-1966 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Heat Resistant Plastics, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Helix Inc., 1961 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Leo H. Hirsch Corporation, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Holly Products Corp., 1961-1964 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Hub Metal Novelty Co., 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Imperial Electro Plating Co. Geneva Metal, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Jem Custom Records Inc., 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Kaycraft, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Lerner, Corwin and Young Inc., 1962-1968 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Leslynn Products Corp., 1965 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Lyndas Jewelry Creation, 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Magna Plastic Plating Inc., 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Mercury Button, 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Mercury Modes Manufacturing Co., 1961 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Miller Brass Fitting, 1960-1965 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- I. Miller and Bro., 1949-1968 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Miller Plastics, Inc., 1961-1967 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Molded Plastic Ear Molds Inc., 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Monarch Jewelry, 1961-1965 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- E.P. Mueller and Engineering, 1961-1966 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Nasco Corp., 1961-1965 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- National Ribbon Co., 1960-1965 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Pal-Playwell, 1961-1969 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Paris Plastic Co. Inc., 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Parmett Plastic Corp., 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Pav Industries Inc. (Amneg Plastics), 1961-1964 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Pender Plastics Co., 1961-1965 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Penmar Novelties Inc., 1966 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Pilot Rubber Plastic Corp., 1959-1965 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Plastic Button, 1961-1968 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Plastic Casting Production, Inc., 1969 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Plastic Mold Powder, 1961-1969 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Plasticite Corp., 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Plas-Trix Co. Inc., 1961-1969 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Queen City Plastics Inc., 1961-1965 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- John Rie Inc., 1961-1969 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Rolling Eyes Manufacturing Co., 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Sanita Plastic Ware Inc., 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Saxony Wool Corp., 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Silver Park Records Inc., 1960-1966 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Soptra Fabrics Corporation, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Strauss and Japo, 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Sussex Newman Plastics Co., 1961-1964 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- V. H. Swenson Inc., 1962 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Thomas Manufacturing Corp., 1958-1964 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Twisted Button Corp., 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Union City Plastics Division of Cavendish Record, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Werner-Klang, 1959-1967 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- White Star, 1964-1970 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Whitestone Harrison Corp., 1961-1970 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Yorklyn Industries Inc., 1961-1965 (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Minutes of the Health and Welfare Fund of the Plastic, Moulders and Novelty Workers Union, Local 132., 1965-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Local 132 Executive Board Minutes., 1965-1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Local 132 News, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  May, 1957
- Local 132 News, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  April, 1973
- Local 132 News, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  June, 1973
- Local 132 News, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  July, 1973
- Local 132 News, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  May, 1976